<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Victoria O&#39;Dell</title>
    <description>Design, Technology, &amp; Community</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 16:14:33 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 16:14:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Imposter Syndrome</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since graduating last May and finding myself as a designer in a tech startup and a leader in a civic tech organization I’ve been in situations that have me influencing decisions and making more decisions. It’s a little overwhelming at times. I sometimes feel like I don’t have enough knowledge or experience to be making or leading anything. I don’t feel adequate as a designer or decision maker and sometimes I question if I’m in the right place or if I belong.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
These, as a lot of you may know, are all symptoms of &lt;em&gt;Imposter Syndrome&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;imposter-syndrome--self-doubt&quot;&gt;Imposter Syndrome &amp;amp; Self-doubt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not familiar with it, Imposter Syndrome is described as a constant fear that you don’t belong or are a fraud. Additionally, “proof of success is dismissed as luck, timing, or as a result of deceiving others into thinking they [you are] more intelligent and competent than [you] believe [yourself] to be.”(&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Post-graduation isn’t the only time I felt like this. When I was leader of an organization on campus I also had this feeling. When I played rugby in college I thought it was a mistake that I was even on the team. I constantly feel removed from the groups I partake in. Like an outsider that has wiggled their way in. Like a bubble that will burst if anyone examines me to closely. It makes me feel defensive and like the knowledge I have and my ideas are not enough. It makes me hyper-critical of any mistakes or missteps I may take. I have a fear of failing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even these past few weeks I’ve held myself back from answerings questions or offering suggestions because I was afraid my ideas weren’t right in the context or in general. And these past few weeks as I stay silent I hear these very same questions and suggestions coming from others with more confidence and experience. This need for constant validation is a little stressful and by staying silent because of the fear of being wrong I feel like I’m losing my voice. And I know I’m not the only one that feels like that. And I know it will take work to stop feeling like that.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understanding-myself&quot;&gt;Understanding Myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping that by talking about it more and understanding myself and my thinking a little better I can avoid these situations and gain confidence. By letting my friends and peers know about my feelings they can help become my instigators of success. Because I can’t do it all and I don’t know anyone that actually can. And although we shouldn’t have to constantly seek validation from others, we have to understand that validation makes us feel human. Having your ideas understood by someone means somethings. Having people that empathize or sympathize with you gives your story and your voice strength.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As I continue working on the things I’m passionate about I’m finding the gaps that I help fill by being present. I’m recognizing that I have not just put myself in places, I’ve also been invited and sometimes chosen to be there. And even if I have to insert myself places that I think I belong, I’m doing so because I’m passionate and have ideas I want to share and are worth sharing.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moving-forward&quot;&gt;Moving forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t stop feeling like an imposter immediately. The fallout from my over-thinking and self-doubt will likely last awhile. I’ll make mistakes and missteps but that’s okay. Today I’m addressing what I feel like. Today I’ll recognize that I got where I am because people believed in me and I believed in myself enough to arrive here.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Tomorrow I’ll remember that I’m not an imposter. I’m a person with ideas, questions, and support. &lt;em&gt;And so are you!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you also feel like an imposter sometimes? Self-doubt blocking you from doing something? Have some encouraging words? I’d love to hear more from you! By writing and socializing more I hope that I can see my achievements, interest, and goals through a more positive lens and help others to do the same.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Victoria_ODell&quot;&gt;Tweet me&lt;/a&gt; a favorite link, send me a dm or feel free to shoot me an &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#118;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#046;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&amp;#063;&amp;#083;&amp;#117;&amp;#098;&amp;#106;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#061;&amp;#076;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#039;&amp;#115;&amp;#037;&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#067;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#116;&amp;#034;&amp;#032;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#061;&amp;#034;&amp;#095;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#034;&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 12:27:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/01/imposter-syndrome.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/05/01/imposter-syndrome.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Website Under Construction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! Thanks for stopping by. I’m currently working on updating my
website. I am working with Jekyll to build a blog into my site and update the look and feel to
better reflect how I feel about myself 1 year out of college.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the process I would like to get a better handle on sass and using Github/Git.
I’m kind of a noob so it might take a bit to get everything up and running in a way that satisfies me.
But, I’m excited about trying something new and being able to add and subtract as I see fit. Any practice
using HTML more effectively and managing CSS and sass is good practice for me.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why Jekyll?&lt;/strong&gt; I was exposed to Jekyll when I started helping with the Open Austin website. I like that it doesn’t require
me to learn PHP or lots of javascript. It also gives me a solid frame with the ability to manipulate elements
in way that makes me feel more in control of my site.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Expect some more post from me very soon and check back on my site as I tweak and adjust it.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;check out Jekyll for yourself&lt;/a&gt; and let me know if you have any tips or tricks for better managing a Jekyll site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 02:16:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2016/04/17/first-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/jekyll/update/2016/04/17/first-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
